adjustable dumbbells are the best bet
for anybody who's tied on space but is
looking for the versatility that
multiple dumbbells bring to the table
plus they're going to save you money
compared to purchasing a full set of
your traditional dumbbells now there's a
lot of options on the market but I've
got a pair of 66 pound adjustables from
a TiVo fit that I want to break down for
y'all they feature an ergonomic handle
with a rubber grip they're pretty easy
to adjust and there's hardly any plastic
involved in the construction I'm pretty
pumped for this one so let's just go
ahead and get right to it
[Music]
all right
what's up y'all it's Jake back in the
barbing garage gym and for today's video
I've got a pair of adjustable dumbbells
from a TiVo fit now if you don't know
how all this works in this video today
I'm going to tell you everything you
need to know about these adjustable
dumbbells from the price and the
features as well as some pros and cons
you might run into and of course who
should or maybe should not add these to
their home gym but before I get going
with all of that I gotta let you know
we've reviewed a ton of adjustable
dumbbells over on barbin.com and if you
want to browse our best list all you got
to do is search bar Ben best adjustable
dumbbells our list is going to pull
right up for you you can find out for
yourself which ones that we like the
best
[Music]
all right so let's take a second and
talk about what I like about these
adjustable dumbbells and we got to kick
this off with the lack of plastic now
there definitely is a little bit
involved but I like how it's you know
pretty much centralized just to the
adjustment mechanism that's really nice
you know durability shouldn't be much of
an issue whatsoever which is really cool
these are also going to replace 12 pairs
of dumbbells with weights ranging from
11 pounds to 66 pounds in five pound
increments so that's nice you can kind
of you know progressively overload your
muscles a little bit slower than a pair
of dumbbells that are only going to have
10 pound increments so that's just
really cool it's also really easy to
adjust the weight all you got to do is
press it on this red button right here
and there's a dial on both sides but you
only have to use one so that's pretty
cool you just click in right there twist
this and it'll go ahead and adjust this
side as well and that's just you know a
nice and easy touch right there for you
these are also pretty affordable
only gonna run you around 330 bucks and
considering you know 66 pounds is
heavier than the average adjustable
dumbbell out there it's actually a
pretty good deal and you know once again
especially since most of this is made
from metal right here I also really like
the stand right here now it's not
included with your purchase it's extra
130 bucks or so but it does have some
Wheels underneath makes it super easy
for you to you know move it around your
personal space also just having your
dumbbells elevated like this is so much
easier to take them out of the cradles
and put them back it's way better than
having them you know stashed on the
ground and then also I really like how
the weight plates have a flat base this
is going to allow you to use them for
push-ups or maybe even burpees if you
want so that's just pretty cool too it
kind of you know adds to the versatility
a little bit
all right now let's you know Veer off a
little bit and talk about a few cons you
might run into and I think first of all
we've got to talk about the length of
these dumbbells so regardless of which
way you're lifting 11 pounds or 66
pounds these are going to be the same
length no matter what and that's just
you know the overall design right here
it's because you know these plates are
getting picked up or left in the Cradle
whenever you're going to lift as opposed
to you know it's like some other ones
where you literally only have you know
this plate or that plate and it kind of
expands as you go up and wait so
definitely keep that in mind and also
you know these rubber grips
might not be ideal for everybody now I
haven't had anything you know negatively
impact me with my grip or anything when
I'm working out but you know I
definitely get it you know some people
are definitely partial you know having a
knurling on your dumbbell handles so
trust me like I said I get it and also
you know it is ergonomically shaped so
it's fatter in the middle than it is on
the ends and not everybody's crazy about
that either both of these things are
personal preference so you definitely
want to keep that in mind but yeah you
know if you're looking for you know
adjustable dumbbells with you know a
fully knurled and a straight handle all
the way across with the same diameter
there's definitely other options out
there for you to consider and then also
the five pound increments are nice you
know not every adjustable dumbbells like
that you know some of them only jump up
in 10 pound increments so not too much
to gripe about but you know with these
lower increments you know 11 pounds you
know 15 pounds 16 pounds all that be
nice to have some two and a half pound
increments and it's you know going to be
really beneficial for accessory
movements you know like lateral raises
y-raises stuff like that where you're
not really trying to necessarily jump up
and wait you know super fast also it can
be a little tricky at times you know
just to get the dumbbells back into the
Cradle it's kind of gets stuck a little
bit and the weight plates are kind of
touching too much so I think over time
you'll get used to it it'll be you know
relatively easy process but something to
keep in mind and then lastly you know
these cradles are in fact made of
plastic so you definitely don't want to
just you know toss these bad boys into
the Cradle because you absolutely run
the risk of them cracking now I'm not
saying these are the most brittle you
know things in the world but it's
definitely a risk one more thing about
weight you know 66 pounds is really nice
as I mentioned earlier the average
adjustable dumbbell does not go up that
high but for somebody who needs heavier
weight than that for your you know
dumbbell bench press maybe even shoulder
press there's other options that can be
as heavy as 80 pounds
[Music]
oh
all right so let's take a second and
talk about some money you know once
again the ativa fit adjustable dumbbells
have a price tag of right around 330
bucks now they come with a two year
warranty plan but you can add on a
three-year plan for about 30 bucks or
The Five-Year Plan for about forty
dollars and once again you know the
stand is not included it's going to run
you around 130 now let's say you go all
in get everything I just mentioned it's
gonna cost you less than 500 and
shipping is free so honestly this is a
really solid deal now there's not too
many options out there that are cheaper
than these are but there's plenty that
are more expensive you know some are
going to run you over eight hundred
dollars maybe even over a thousand
dollars So at the end of the day you
know this is a really solid deal
considering the overall quality you know
there's hardly any plastic involved so
durability should not be an issue and
these are going to last you a really
long time
all right so now let's break down the
build and some of the features with
these adjustable dumbbells so once again
you know this isn't ergonomically shaped
handle and if you don't know what that
is maybe you forgot maybe I forgot to
mention it earlier I can't remember
because I've been talking so much
ergonomic handles they're a little bit
thicker in the middle than they are on
the end so definitely keep that in mind
it's personal preference that everybody
likes now the rubber grip right here
pretty nice you know it does give me a
pretty solid grip as I'm working out but
that might not be ideal for everybody so
once again just keep that in mind I like
how there's not a whole lot of plastic
involved right here especially with
these weight plates you know even where
they connect to the actual you know
handle there's not any plastic on the
plate which is nice and plus they're
they have a flat bottom so once again
you know you are able to incorporate
some push-ups with these maybe some
burpees you know do different things
with them just adds to the versatility
now
the actual adjustment mechanism these
dials are plastic but I think it's going
to be fine in the long run now it's
really easy to adjust the weight you
just press down on these red buttons
right here and then you're free to go
and adjust it and I really really like
how you don't have to adjust on both
sides like you have to do with some you
know similar adjustable dumbbells and
that's just really cool it's going to
cut down you know on that you know time
you're spent adjusting your weight now
the cradles themselves are also plastic
so you definitely you know don't want to
just toss these bad boys in there
because you could definitely
crack that you definitely want that to
happen I really like the stand you know
it is made from steel don't know what
gauge there is some welding down here
but you know end of the day it's going
to get the job done you know I don't see
you know any stability or durability
issues with this stand whatsoever now
if you're not purchasing the stand and
you're just going to rely on the cradles
to you know store them in your home
they're a little over 16 inches long
about eight inches wide and about eight
inches tall all right so let's go ahead
and give you guys a nice up close look
at the build and everything of these
adjustable dumbbells kind of demonstrate
how everything operates so I want to
talk about these handles first
once again they are ergonomically shaped
so they're thicker right here in the
middle than they are in the ends and
this rubber grip might not be ideal for
everybody but you know it's designed for
a reason and that reason is to give you
a good grip so at the end of the day
it's not that bad now adjusting the
weight it's really easy just press down
on this red button
and then you just twist this knob right
here and then you're good to go and you
don't have to do it on both sides just
one side you can do it on that side and
press the button down if you want it
doesn't matter now as we pull this out
this is the same link
you're gonna have no matter what so if
you had it on 66 pounds obviously going
to be maxed out like this but around 11
pounds so it's just the overall design
might not be ideal for everybody now not
a whole lot of plastic involved here
except for you know right in here so
these red like liners that's all plastic
white Parts plastic and then obviously
you know right here and here that's
plastic now you know might not be ideal
for everybody but I like how it's you
know centrally located in that one spot
and then I want to talk about these
weight plates so
a lot of times with adjustable dumbbells
all of this right here will be lined
with plastic but these are all steel
there is no plastic whatsoever so you
know that's even better in terms of
durability it's gonna you know last you
longer I also really like how all of
these plates are flat on the bottom
right there you know it really unlocks
the ability to do push-ups burpees
whatever I like doing push-ups with
dumbbells because it keeps my wrist in a
natural position so it's nice how you
can do that here now
putting the handle back can be a little
bit of a hassle so let's see if it works
right here for me the first try it
doesn't so there we go so sometimes you
just have to mess with the plates a
little bit because they kind of lean up
against one another
it's not that bad you'll get used to it
in the long run another kind of quirky
thing right here is actually the
labeling so 11 pounds right here these
are all five pound increments but they
flip flop all right so you got 16 here
21 here 26 and 31 and it just kind of
keeps doing that all the way around now
definitely works but for my you know my
brain how I kind of want things to work
it's a little bit funky it's not that
big of a deal to get used to it now
obviously you know once again these
cradles are made of plastic so
definitely you don't want to be Reckless
whenever you go to you know house your
dumbbells just be a little cautious with
them and I really like this stand you
know you got your wheels so it makes it
really easy for you to slide these
around your own personal space and also
like how you can actually angle these
stands these trays so I have it at a
eight degree angle right now which is
nice you know it's going to make it a
little easier for you to grab them pull
them out and put them back obviously but
you can also have them you know
completely flat if you prefer there's
also a strap right here
I don't think you necessarily need it if
you don't want to but you know they
these cradles are held in by screws and
if they come loose you know it's a nice
little safety blanket right there now
while I got you here let's go ahead and
just do a little demonstration we're on
11 pounds already so you know this is
going to be perfect for your lateral
raises you know your y raises all those
you know simple you know accessory
movements but
see if we can get this to go in here I'm
telling you it definitely gets stuck a
little bit on you
be careful with your finger too because
I about just took mine off that that
hurt I'm not gonna lie to y'all let's go
ahead and add some heavier weight on
here I'm just gonna go over 21 pounds
right now you know you can sit here and
do your hammer curls you know your
regular bicep curls whatever and if you
can hear that there is a little bit you
know of movement right there with the
plates now it doesn't really throw me
off but I could throw you off and it
might just be a little bit annoying
honestly more than anything so
definitely remember that in the long run
so really you know there's just a lot of
stuff you can do here can't forget about
the 66 pounds you know good for shoulder
press good for your you know your
dumbbell rows your dumbbell bench press
there's a lot going on split squats I
mean goblet squats dumbbells just really
get the job done for me and especially
since these are really compact compared
to you know having a full set
it's a really nice touch right here and
then one more thing I don't know if you
guys have noticed but these are eerily
similar to the Bowflex selectec 552s
which I happen to have right here but I
will say the ativa fits are an upgrade
in my opinion so
these have a lot more plastic a whole
lot more plastic pretty much everything
right here is lined in plastic and then
also you have to adjust the weight on
both sides and these have to match for
you to be able to pull the dumbbells out
and then also these seem a little bit
bigger a little bit longer
I don't have my measuring tape on me or
else I'd you know measure them right now
head to head for you guys but you know
this is the most similar product I found
on the market and honestly the ativa
fits they're a nice upgrade
[Music]
okay so who should purchase the ativa
fit adjustable dumbbells well let's talk
about space and money it's the two for
one right here if you're tied on both of
those this is a really solid option you
know adjustable dumbbells in general are
going to be nice if you're tight on
space but these specific ones you know
really high quality there's hardly any
plastic involved a whole lot of metal
involved and you know at the end of the
day you know 330 dollar price tag is
really tough to beat so if you're tight
on both of those things you probably
should be jumping on these bad boys
right here and then also you know 66
pounds is more than the average
adjustable dumbbell so the average
weight lifter this is going to be a
really solid weight range for you
[Music]
all right now what about the people who
might not want to purchase these and
let's talk about the weight range first
I know I just got done saying 66 pounds
is more than the average adjustable
dumbbell it's gonna be nice for the
average weight lifter those are still
true those are still true statements but
you know me personally for my dumbbell
bench press specifically I need heavier
than 66 pounds and I'm sure there's
plenty of y'all out there that feel the
same way so you know
if that's the case you're going to have
to check out some other options but you
know at the end of the day you know
accessory work stuff like that it's
still going to be pretty nice for you
now let's talk about the actual shape
and the design as well you know the
length is the length does not change a
little over 16 inches and there's other
compact options out there so you know if
you are wanting one of those more
compact options definitely check them
out and then lastly you know obviously
there is a little bit of plastic
involved not too much compared to some
other ones out there but it's still
there its presence is still felt in you
know certain ways so you know there are
other ones that don't feature any
plastic at all they're going to cost you
more money but you know if you're
worried about durability and you just
want to avoid plastic all together it
might be worth checking out those other
options
[Music]
foreign
that's all I got for y'all today on the
ativa fit adjustable dumbbells I
personally really like these you know
they feel really durable in my hands
there's a whole lot of metal involved in
the construction they're going to
replace 12 pairs of dumbbells it's
pretty easy to adjust the weight and
then the price is honestly really tough
to beat just remember there is a little
bit of plastic involved it's pretty much
centralized just to the cradles and the
adjustment mechanism right here
definitely keep that in mind and then
also the length is not going to change
no matter what thanks for hanging out
with me y'all I hope this video was
really helpful that I was able to break
down everything you need to know about
these adjustable dumbbells as always
stay posted for my next video but for
now head over to barbin.com because we
have a full written review ready to go
for y'all all you got to do is search
bar Bend ativa fit adjustable dumbbell
review it's going to pull right up for
you you can go over every single thing
we talked about here today I'll catch
y'all next time
foreign
[Music]